Register of the Milan Gavrilović Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Speeches and Writings,., 1947-1979 (Box 19-30, Reel 21-38)
  - "Coerced Federation,"., 1952 July 8 (Box-folder 29: 18, Reel 36)
    Lecture at the Institute of Public Affairs and Regional Studies, New York University. Typescript and printed copy. Includes Serbo-Croatian translation
  - "Samovlasni Tutori,"., 1952 September 10 (Reel 37, Box-folder 29: 19)
    Printed copy (in Serbo-Croatian)
  - "Mali Jova,"., 1952 October 23 (Reel 37, Box-folder 29: 20)
  - "Žarište Mržnje," Glas Kanadskikh Srba,., 1953 January 5 (Reel 37, Box-folder 29: 21)
  - "Marks i Engels o Seljaštvu i Srpskom Narodu," Glas Kanadskikh Srba,., 1953 January-February (Reel 37, Box-folder 29: 22)
  - "'Novi' Privredni System," Glas Kanadskikh Srba,., 1953 February 19 (Reel 37, Box-folder 29: 23)
  - "Na Bespuću," Glas Kanadskikh Srba,., 1953 March 26 (Reel 37, Box-folder 29: 24)
  - "Ustavna Opsena," Glas Kanadskikh Srba,., 1953 April 30 (Reel 37, Box-folder 29: 25)
  - "Korak Natrag, Dva Napred - Ako Stignu," Glas Kanadskikh Srba,., 1953 August 6 (Reel 37, Box-folder 29: 26)
  - "Koreja," Glas Kanadskikh Srba,., 1953 September 3 (Reel 37, Box-folder 29: 27)
  - "Govor Dr. M. Gavrilovića na Proslavi Vidovdana,"., 1954 (Box-folder 30: 1, Reel 37)
  - "Govor Dr. Gavrilovica na Kongresu SNO,"., 1954 June 28 (Reel 37, Box-folder 30: 2)
  - "Report on Yugoslavia,"., 1954 September 28 (Reel 37, Box-folder 30: 3)
  - "Dva Dokumenta," Sloboda/Liberty,., 1956 January 4 (Reel 37, Box-folder 30: 4)
  - "A Dying Ideology and Its Foreign Policy," an address at the VI Congress of the International Peasant Union,., 1959 May 30-31 (Box-folder 30: 5, Reel 37)
    Typescript with annotated draft
  - "Srbi i Jugoslavija,"., 1960 May (Reel 37, Box-folder 30: 6)
  - Speech, Action Committee for Organization of the All Serbian Congress,., 1960 May 26 (Reel 38, Box-folder 30: 7)
  - "Saopštenje Srpskoj Javnosti,"., 1960 July 25 (Box-folder 30: 8, Reel 38)
  - "Hannibal Ad Portas,"., 1960 August 20 (Box-folder 30: 9, Reel 38)
    Typescript and printed copy. Includes Serbo-Croatian translation
  - "Govor Dr. Milana Gavrilovića," Sloboda/Liberty,., 1960 September 1 (Box-folder 30: 10, Reel 38)
  - "Borba Na Život i Smrt," Glas Kanadskih Srba,., 1960 October 6 (Reel 38, Box-folder 30: 11)
  - "Lomaća Usred Beograda,"., 1960 October 10 (Reel 38, Box-folder 30: 12)
  - Speech, XVIII Congress of Serbian National Defense (SNO),., 1960 October 27 (Reel 38, Box-folder 30: 13)
  - Speech, Congress of Serbian National Defense for Eastern States of USA,., 1960 December 10 (Reel 38, Box-folder 30: 14)
  - Report to the Serbian National Council,., 1961 June 28 (Reel 38, Box-folder 30: 15)
    Typescript with annotations. Includes Serbo-Croatian translation
  - Speech at the International Peasant Union Congress,., 1961 September 3 (Reel 38, Box-folder 30: 16)
  - "Politički Portreti: Nikola Pasic," Glas Kanadskich Srba ( Voice of Canadian Serbs),., 1962 November 29 (Reel 38, Box-folder 30: 17)
  - "Smena Generacija,"., 1963 February 28 (Reel 38, Box-folder 30: 18)
  - "O Crkvenom Pitanju,"., 1964 December (Reel 38, Box-folder 30: 19)
  - "O Komunizmu,"., 1966 (Reel 38, Box-folder 30: 20)
    Draft, typescript and correspondence (in Serbo-Croatian)
  - "Komunizam je Ponikao iz Mržnje," Sloboda/Liberty,., 1967 January 4 (Reel 38, Box-folder 30: 21)
  - "Srpski Narode,"., 1968 May (Reel 38, Box-folder 30: 22)
  - "Narode Srpski,"., 1968 October (Reel 38, Box-folder 30: 23)
  - "Dr. Miloš Tupanjanin," Sloboda/Liberty,., 1969 March 12 (Box-folder 30: 24, Reel 38)
  - "Two Simple Questions and One Simple Answer,"., 1972 December 15 (Box-folder 30: 25, Reel 38)
    Holograph and typescript. Includes Serbo-Croatian translation
  - Speech upon the 20th anniversary of Konstantin Fotić's death,., 1979 (Reel 38, Box-folder 30: 26)
- Envoy to the Soviet Union Office File,., 1940-1941 (Box 31, Box 31-32, Reel 38-41)
  Correspondence, government documents, memoranda, notes, reports, clippings and printed matter. Arranged alphabetically by form or subject
  - General (Reel 38, Box-folder 31: 1)
  - Correspondence (Reel 38, Box-folder 31: 2)
  - Excerpts from Soviet newspapers and periodicals (Reel 38, Box-folder 31: 3)
  - Financial records (Reel 39-40, Box-folder 31: 4-7)
  - Financial records (Reel 40, Box-folder 32: 1)
  - Reports from Moscow (Reel 40, Box-folder 32: 2-3)
- Yugoslav Government in Exile, London,., 1941-1943 (Reel 40-42, Box 32-33)
  - General
    - General (Reel 41, Box-folder 32: 4)
    - Clippings (Reel 41, Box-folder 32: 5)
    - Correspondence (Reel 41, Box-folder 32: 6)
    - Financial reports (Reel 41, Box-folder 32: 7)
    - Political reports (Reel 41, Box-folder 32: 8)
    - Political reports (Box-folder 33: 1-2, Reel 41)
  - Cairo office. (Box-folder 33: 3, Reel 41)
    Correspondence, reports
  - Yugoslav Information Office. (Box-folder 33: 4, Reel 42)
    Reports
  - Yugoslavia. Army. (Box-folder 33: 5, Reel 42)
  - Yugoslavia. Embassy (Great Britain) (Box-folder 33: 6, Reel 42)
- Serbian National Committee (Srpski Nationalni Odbor - SNO),., 1952-1975 (Reel 41-48, Box 33-38)
  Bulletins, correspondence, memoranda, notes, reports, clippings and printed matter. Arranged alphabetically by form or subject and chronologically
  - General (Box-folder 33: 7, Reel 42)
  - Bulletins, open letters, statutes (Box-folder 33: 8, Reel 42)
  - Bulletins, open letters, statutes (Reel 43, Box-folder 34: 1)
  - Correspondence
    - General (Reel 43, Box-folder 34: 2)
    - Aćin, Miloš Kosta, 1972 (Reel 43, Box-folder 34: 3)
    - Aranicki, Miloje S., 1968 (Reel 43, Box-folder 34: 4)
    - Associação Serbo-Brasileira, 1960 (Reel 43, Box-folder 34: 5)
    - Association d'Entr'aide des Yougoslaves en Suisse, 1973-1974 (Reel 43, Box-folder 34: 6)
    - Association "Milan Nedić,", 1952-1973 (Reel 43, Box-folder 34: 7)
    - Bayar, Celal, 1954 (Box-folder 34: 8, Reel 43)
    - Brandt, Willy (Box-folder 34: 9, Reel 43)
    - Brkić, Jovan A., 1969 (Box-folder 34: 10, Reel 43)
    - Brock, Bill, 1974 (Box-folder 34: 11, Reel 43)
    - Bulat, Pero, 1960 (Box-folder 34: 12, Reel 43)
    - Canada. Office of the Prime Minister, 1973 (Box-folder 34: 13, Reel 43)
    - Church, Marguerite Stitt, 1962 (Box-folder 34: 14, Reel 43)
    - Dalhousie University, Halifax, Nova Scotia (Hicks, Henry D.), 1971 (Box-folder 34: 16, Reel 43)
    - Communauté Serbe en Belgique, 1962 (Box-folder 34: 15, Reel 43)
    - Delmas, Chaban, 1970 (Reel 43, Box-folder 34: 17)
    - Derwinski, Edward, 1967 (Reel 43, Box-folder 34: 18)
    - Dirksen, Everett M., 1962 (Reel 43, Box-folder 34: 19)
    - Durović, Wm. M., 1972 (Reel 43, Box-folder 34: 20)
    - Eisenhower, Dwight D., 1955-1960 (Reel 43, Box-folder 34: 21)
    - Elizabeth II, Queen of England, 1972 (Reel 43, Box-folder 34: 22)
    - Engle, Clair, 1962 (Reel 43, Box-folder 34: 23)
    - Eyskens, M. Gaston, 1970 (Reel 43, Box-folder 34: 24)
    - Gaulle, Charles de, 1960-1967 (Box-folder 34: 25, Reel 43)
    - Germany. Chancellor and Foreign Affairs Minister, 1968 (Box-folder 34: 26, Reel 43)
    - Irinej, Bishop, 1971 (Box-folder 34: 27, Reel 43)
    - Israel. Embassy (United States), 1972 (Box-folder 34: 28, Reel 43)
    - Johnson, Lyndon B., 1967-1968 (Box-folder 34: 29, Reel 43)
    - Jovanović, Radmilo, 1964 (Box-folder 34: 30, Reel 43)
    - Kennedy, John F., 1962 (Box-folder 34: 31, Reel 43)
    - Kiderlen, Hans Rolf, 1961 (Box-folder 34: 32, Reel 43)
    - Klaus, Julius, 1968 (Reel 43, Box-folder 34: 33)
    - Konstantin, King of Greece, 1967 (Reel 43, Box-folder 34: 34)
    - Korach, Rade, 1965-1968 (Reel 44, Box-folder 34: 35)
    - Kuchel, Thomas H., 1962 (Reel 44, Box-folder 34: 36)
    - Lausche, Frank J., 1963-1965 (Reel 44, Box-folder 34: 37)
    - Macmillan, Harold, 1960 (Reel 44, Box-folder 34: 38)
    - McKisson, Robert M., 1970 (Reel 44, Box-folder 34: 39)
    - McVey, Walter L., 1962 (Reel 44, Box-folder 34: 40)
    - Milosavljević, Petar M., 1972 (Box-folder 34: 41, Reel 44)
    - Mollet, Guy, 1956 (Reel 44, Box-folder 34: 42)
    - Movement of Serbian Chetniks, Ravne Gore in Great Britain, 1960-1963 (Box-folder 34: 43, Reel 44)
    - Narodni Odbor za Sloveniju, 1974 (Box-folder 34: 44, Reel 44)
    - Nixon, Richard M. (Box 35)
      - 1968 (Box-folder 35: 1, Reel 44)
      - 1969 (Box-folder 35: 2, Reel 44)
      - 1969-1971 (Box-folder 35: 3, Reel 44)
      - 1971-1973 (Box-folder 35: 4, Reel 44)
    - Nobel Peace Price Committee, 1972 (Reel 44, Box-folder 35: 5)
    - Papagos, Alexandre, 1954 (Box-folder 35: 6, Reel 44)
    - Paul, King of Greece, 1954 (Reel 44, Box-folder 35: 7)
    - Paul VI, Pope, 1970 (Reel 44, Box-folder 35: 8)
    - Peter II, King of Yugoslavia, n.d. (Reel 44, Box-folder 35: 9)
    - Pillion, John R., 1962 (Reel 44, Box-folder 35: 10)
    - Polish Council of National Unity, American Division, 1955 (Reel 44, Box-folder 35: 11)
    - Pompidou, Georges, 1969-1970 (Reel 44, Box-folder 35: 12)
    - Privrednik (Brussels), 1974 (Reel 44, Box-folder 35: 13)
    - Radni Odbor za Doček Nj. V. Kralja Petra II u Americi (Savić, Svetomir), 1963 (Box-folder 35: 14, Reel 44)
    - Radojević, Buro, Dr., 1972 (Box-folder 35: 15, Reel 44)
    - Rarick, John R., 1968 (Box-folder 35: 16, Reel 44)
    - "Ravna Gora," Milwaukee, Wisconsin, 1969 (Box-folder 35: 17, Reel 44)
    - Ravnogorski Narodni Pokret u Francuskoj (Paris), 1969 (Box-folder 35: 18, Reel 44)
    - Rusk, Dean, 1965 (Box-folder 35: 19, Reel 44)
    - Saragatti, Giuseppe, 1969-1970 (Reel 44, Folder 35: 20)
    - Savez Zemljoradnika (Chicago), 1961-1975 (Reel 44, Box-folder 35: 21)
    - Schadeberg, Henry C., 1962 (Box-folder 35: 22, Reel 44)
    - Serbian League of Canada, 1966-1972 (Box-folder 35: 23, Reel 44)
    - Serbian National Club, Berne, Switzerland, 1973 (Box-folder 35: 24, Reel 44)
    - Serbian National Committee for Europe, 1971-1973 (Reel 44, Box-folder 35: 25)
    - Serbian National Defense Council in Australia, 1967-1972 (Reel 44, Box-folder 35: 26)
    - Serbian National Defense Council in the Federal Republic of Germany, 1971 (Reel 44, Box-folder 35: 27)
    - Serbian National Defense "Gavrilo Princip," Adelaide, Australia, 1963-1966 (Reel 44, Box-folder 35: 28)
    - Short, Don L., 1962 (Box-folder 35: 29, Reel 44)
    - Smith, H. Allen, 1962 (Box-folder 35: 30, Reel 44)
    - South Africa. Ministry of Police and Justice (Kruger, J. T.), 1974 (Box-folder 35: 31, Reel 44)
    - Srpski Glasnik (Canberra, Australia), 1968 (Box-folder 35: 32, Reel 44)
    - Srpski Ravnogorski Pokret, Sydney, Australia, 1970 (Box-folder 35: 33, Reel 44)
    - Srpski Savetodavni Odbor za Francusku, 1961-1964 (Box-folder 35: 34, Reel 44)
    - Stanišić, Branislav M.
      - Undated (Box-folder 35: 35, Reel 45)
      - 1959-1962 (Box-folder 36: 1, Reel 45)
      - 1963 (Reel 45, Box-folder 36: 2)
      - 1964 (Reel 45, Box-folder 36: 3)
      - 1965 (Reel 45, Box-folder 36: 4)
      - 1966 (Reel 45, Box-folder 36: 5)
      - 1967 (Reel 46, Box-folder 36: 6)
      - 1968 (Reel 46, Box-folder 36: 7)
      - 1969 (Reel 46, Box-folder 37: 1)
      - 1969-1970 (Reel 46, Box-folder 37: 2)
      - 1971 (Reel 47, Box-folder 37: 3)
      - 1972 (Reel 47, Box-folder 37: 4)
      - 1973 (Reel 47, Box-folder 38: 1)
      - 1974-1975 (Reel 47, Box-folder 38: 2)
    - Stojanović, Milan, 1972 (Reel 47, Box-folder 38: 3)
    - Sweden. Ministry for Foreign Affairs, 1970 (Reel 47, Box-folder 38: 4)
    - Talmadge, Herman E., 1962 1974 (Reel 47, Box-folder 38: 5)
    - Tice, Donald, 1970 (Reel 47, Box-folder 38: 6)
    - Tomislav, 1961 (Reel 47, Box-folder 38: 7)
    - Topalović, Tihomir, 1969 (Reel 47, Box-folder 38: 8)
    - Trivunac, Stevan, 1962 (Reel 47, Box-folder 38: 9)
    - Trudeau, Pierre Elliott, 1970 (Reel 47, Box-folder 38: 10)
    - United Nations Commission on Human Rights, 1969 (Reel 47, Box-folder 38: 11)
    - United States. Department of Justice, 1970 (Reel 47, Box-folder 38: 12)
    - United States. Department of State, 1954-1965 (Reel 47, Box-folder 38: 13)
    - United States. Office of the Vice President, 1970 (Reel 47, Box-folder 38: 14)
    - Université de Paris, Bibliothèque de Documentation Internationale, 1973 (Reel 47, Box-folder 38: 15)
    - Vaes, J., 1970 (Reel 47, Box-folder 38: 16)
    - Vardelja, Dragoljub, 1967 (Reel 47, Box-folder 38: 17)
    - Verheye, Pierre, 1974 (Reel 47, Box-folder 38: 18)
    - Vujović, N., n.d. (Reel 47, Box-folder 38: 19)
    - Vukčevič, Aleksandar, 1960 (Reel 47, Box-folder 38: 20)
    - Zarić, Milisav, 1963 (Reel 47, Box-folder 38: 21)
    - Związek Przyjaciół Wsi Polskiej w Ameryce, 1958 (Reel 47, Box-folder 38: 22)
  - Memoranda and open letters (Reel 48, Box-folder 38: 23)
  - Printed matter (Reel 48, Box-folder 38: 24-25)
  - Youngstown Congress file, 1960 November (Reel 48, Box-folder 38: 26)
- Subject File,., 1939-1975 (Reel 48-60, Box 39-47)
  Correspondence, memoranda, reports, notes, printed matter, clippings, and other materials. Arranged alphabetically by subject
  - Albania, 1942-1960 (Reel 48, Box-folder 39: 1)
  - Bulgaria, 1942 (Reel 48, Box-folder 39: 2)
  - Czechoslovakia, n.d. (Reel 49, Box-folder 39: 3)
  - Estonia, 1941 (Reel 49, Box-folder 39: 4)
  - Germany, 1918-1949 (Reel 49, Box-folder 39: 5)
  - Great Britain. House of Commons, 1943-1944 (Reel 49, Box-folder 39: 6)
  - Hungary, n.d. (Reel 49, Box-folder 39: 7)
  - International organizations
    - Assembly of Captive European Nations (Reel 49, Box-folder 39: 8)
    - Council on Foreign Relations (Reel 49, Box-folder 39: 9)
    - Court of World Public Opinion (Reel 49, Box-folder 39: 10)
    - Free Europe Committee (Reel 49, Box-folder 39: 11)
    - International Rescue Committee (Reel 49, Box-folder 39: 12)
    - Polish-Hungarian World Federation (Reel 49, Box-folder 39: 13)
    - Publications (Reel 49, Box-folder 39: 14)
  - International Peasant Union (IPU)
    - Correspondence, 1947-1969 (Reel 49, Box-folder 39: 15)
    - Memoranda, circular letters, reports (Reel 50, Box-folder 40: 1-4)
    - Periodicals, publications (Reel 50-51, Box-folder 40: 5-7)
  - Italy, 1945 (Reel 51, Box-folder 41: 1)
  - Maps (Reel 51, Box-folder 41: 2)
  - Mihailović, Draža (Reel 51-52, Box-folder 41: 3-6)
  - Peter II, King of Yugoslavia
    - Clippings (Reel 52, Box-folder 41: 7)
    - Correspondence, 1945-1971 (Reel 52, Box-folder 41: 8)
    - Memoranda, reports, printed matter (Reel 52, Box-folder 42: 1)
  - Poland, 1941-1946 (Reel 52, Box-folder 42: 2)
  - Romania, 1943-1944 (Reel 52, Box-folder 42: 3)
  - Serbian and Yugoslav organizations in exile
    - General
      - General (Reel 53, Box-folder 42: 4)
      - Publications
        - A-E (Reel 53, Box-folder 42: 5)
        - G (Reel 53, Box-folder 42: 6)
        - G-J (Reel 53, Box-folder 42: 7)
        - K-O (Reel 54, Box-folder 42: 8)
        - P-R (Reel 54, Box-folder 42: 9)
        - S (Reel 54, Box-folder 43: 1)
        - T-Z (Reel 54, Box-folder 43: 2)
    - Američki Srpski Odbor za Izbeglice, 1961 (Reel 54, Box-folder 43: 3)
    - Central National Committee of Yugoslavia, 1945 (Reel 54, Box-folder 43: 4)
    - Čikaški Radni Odbor za Doček Nj. V. Kralja Petra II, 1963 (Reel 54, Box-folder 43: 5)
    - Constantin Fotich Fund, 1964 1967 (Reel 55, Box-folder 43: 6)
    - Crkveni Savet u Velikoj Britaniji, n.d. (Reel 55, Box-folder 43: 7)
    - Fond Nacionalne Borbe "Zemlja-Emigracija,", 1969-1970 (Reel 55, Box-folder 43: 8)
    - Glavni Odbor Srba u Hrvatskoj Slavoniji i Dalmaciji, n.d. (Reel 55, Box-folder 43: 9)
    - Hrvatska Seljačka Stranka u Emigraciji, 1944-1945 (Reel 55, Box-folder 43: 10)
    - Jugoslovenska Demokratska Narodna Zajednica, Centralni Komitet u Inostranstvu, 1945 (Reel 55, Box-folder 43: 11)
    - Jugoslovenska Demokratska Narodna Zajednica u Svajcarskoj, 1945 (Reel 55, Box-folder 43: 12)
    - Jugoslovenski Narodni Odbor (London), 1946-1959 (Reel 55, Box-folder 43: 13)
    - Jugoslovenski Odbor iz Italije, 1944 (Reel 55, Box-folder 43: 14)
    - Mouvement Fédéraliste Serbe, 1965 (Reel 55, Box-folder 43: 15)
    - Narodna Radikalna Stranka u Francuskoj, 1960 (Reel 55, Box-folder 43: 16)
    - Narodna Radikalna Stranka u Izgnanstvu, 1960-1966 (Reel 55, Box-folder 43: 17)
    - Narodneg Odbor za Sloveniju, 1944-1946 (Reel 55, Box-folder 43: 18)
    - National Committee of the Kingdom of Yugoslavia in Salzburg, 1945 (Reel 55, Box-folder 43: 19)
    - Njegoš (Chicago), 1970-1975 (Reel 55, Box-folder 43: 20)
    - Privrednik, 1974 (Reel 55, Box-folder 43: 21)
    - Ratnici Draže Mihailovića u Belgiji, 1962 (Reel 55, Box-folder 43: 22)
    - Ravna Gora, 1962-1963 (Reel 55, Box-folder 43: 23)
    - Savet za Oslobodjenje Naroda Jugoslavije, 1953 (Reel 55, Box-folder 43: 24)
    - Savez Srpskih Zemljoradnika, 1953-1967 (Reel 55, Box-folder 43: 25)
    - Savez Zemljoradnika za Ameriku, 1957 1964 (Reel 55, Box-folder 44: 1)
    - Serb National Federation, 1945 (Reel 55, Box-folder 44: 2)
    - Serbian Brothers Help (Chicago), 1968 (Reel 55, Box-folder 44: 3)
    - Serbian National Community, 1948 1962 (Reel 55, Box-folder 44: 4)
    - Serbian National Defense (Chicago), 1958-1968 (Reel 55, Box-folder 44: 5)
    - Serbian National Defense Council in Australia, 1972 (Reel 55, Box-folder 44: 6)
    - Serbian National Defense Council of America (Aliquippa, Pennsylvania), 1961 (Reel 55, Box-folder 44: 7)
    - Serbian National Fund (Canada), 1970 (Reel 55, Box-folder 44: 8)
    - Serbian Peoples University of Chicago, 1967-1975 (Reel 55, Box-folder 44: 9)
    - Society of Serbian Writers and Artists Abroad (London), 1975 (Reel 55, Box-folder 44: 10)
    - Srpska Narodna Koalicija, n.d. (Reel 55, Box-folder 44: 11)
    - Srpska Zajednica u Belgiji, 1962 (Reel 55, Box-folder 44: 12)
    - Srpski Nacionalno-Kulturni Klub u Švajcarskoj, 1963 1967 (Reel 55, Box-folder 44: 13)
    - Srpski Narodni Odbor u Kanadi, 1962 1968 (Reel 55, Box-folder 44: 14)
    - Srpski Savetodavni Odbor u Francuskoj, 1961 (Reel 55, Box-folder 44: 15)
    - Srpski Savetodavni Odbor za Francusku, 1961-1965 (Reel 55, Box-folder 44: 16)
    - Udruženje Boraca Kraljevske Jugoslovenske Vojske "Draža Mihailović,", 1956 1962 1969 (Reel 55, Box-folder 44: 17)
    - Udruženje Jugoslovena u Švajcarskoj za Uzajamnu Pomoć, 1969-1971 (Reel 55, Box-folder 44: 18)
    - Udruženje Jugoslovenskih Novinara u Londonu, 1943 (Reel 55, Box-folder 44: 19)
    - Udruženje Srpskih Pisaca u Izgnanstvu (London), 1951-1970 (Reel 55, Box-folder 44: 20)
    - Union Yugoslave des Fédéralistes (Paris), 1967-1971 (Reel 55, Box-folder 44: 21)
    - Yugoslav Relief Society (London), 1945 (Reel 55, Box-folder 44: 22)
    - Yugoslav Society of Great Britain, 1943 (Reel 55-56, Box-folder 44: 23)
  - Serbian Orthodox Church (Bishop Dionisije)
    - Clippings, 1962-1963 (Reel 56, Box-folder 44: 24)
    - Correspondence
      - General, 1957-1974 (Reel 56, Box-folder 44: 25)
      - Gavrilović, Milan, 1945-1969 (Reel 56, Box-folder 44: 26)
    - Documents relating to the schism, 1963 (Reel 56, Box-folder 44: 27)
    - Memoranda, open letter, resolutions (Reel 56, Box-folder 44: 28)
    - Periodicals and printed matter (Reel 56, Box-folder 45: 1)
  - Yugoslavia
    - General
      - Undated (Reel 56, Box-folder 45: 2)
      - 1940-1942 (Reel 57, Box-folder 45: 3)
      - 1943-1945 (Reel 57, Box-folder 45: 4)
      - 1945 (Reel 57, Box-folder 45: 5)
      - 1946 (Reel 57, Box-folder 45: 6)
    - Communist rule, 1944-1972 (Reel 57, Box-folder 46: 1)
    - Croatia, 1939-1943 (Reel 58, Box-folder 46: 2)
    - Djilas, Milovan, 1968-1969 (Reel 58, Box-folder 46: 3)
    - "Dossier Yugoslavia,", 1942 (Reel 58, Box-folder 46: 4)
    - OZNA atrocities, 1945 (Reel 58, Box-folder 46: 5)
    - Politics and government
      - Report, 1939 (Reel 58, Box-folder 46: 6)
      - Sajković, Ivan S. (Reel 58, Box-folder 46: 7)
    - Publications by Yugoslav communists (Reel 58, Box-folder 46: 8)
    - Slovenia, 1940s (Reel 58, Box-folder 46: 9)
    - Tito, Josip Broz (Reel 58, Box-folder 46: 10)
    - United States. Congress. Issuances, 1947-1968 (Reel 58, Box-folder 47: 1)
    - Ustaši - Trial of 50 Ustaši in Zagreb, 1948 (Reel 58, Box-folder 47: 2)
    - World War, 1914-1918 (Reel 58, Box-folder 47: 3)
    - World War, 1939-1945 (Reel 59, Box-folder 47: 4-5)
  - Miscellany (Reel 59, Box-folder 47: 6-7)
- Clippings,., 1938-1976 (Reel 60-65, Box 47-51)
  Clippings arranged chronologically
  - Undated (Reel 59, Box-folder 47: 8-9)
  - 1938 (Reel 59, Box-folder 47: 10)
  - 1941 (Reel 60, Box-folder 47: 11)
  - 1942 (Reel 60, Box-folder 48: 1)
  - 1943 (Reel 60, Box-folder 48: 2)
  - 1944 (Reel 60, Box-folder 48: 3)
  - 1945 (Reel 60, Box-folder 48: 4)
  - 1946 (Reel 60, Box-folder 48: 5-6)
  - 1947 (Reel 60, Box-folder 48: 7)
  - 1948 (Reel 60, Box-folder 48: 8)
  - 1949 (Reel 60, Box-folder 48: 9)
  - 1950 (Reel 60, Box-folder 48: 10)
  - 1951 (Reel 60, Box-folder 48: 11)
  - 1952 (Reel 60, Box-folder 48: 12)
  - 1953 (Reel 60, Box-folder 48: 13)
  - 1954 (Reel 61, Box-folder 48: 14)
  - 1955 (Reel 61, Box-folder 49: 1)
  - 1956 (Reel 61, Box-folder 49: 2)
  - 1957 (Reel 61, Box-folder 49: 3)
  - 1958 (Reel 61, Box-folder 49: 4)
  - 1959 (Reel 61, Box-folder 49: 5)
  - 1960 (Reel 62, Box-folder 49: 6-8)
  - 1961 (Reel 63, Box-folder 50: 1-2)
  - 1962 (Reel 63, Box-folder 50: 3)
  - 1963 (Reel 63, Box-folder 50: 4)
  - 1964 (Reel 63, Box-folder 50: 5)
  - 1965 (Reel 63, Box-folder 50: 6)
  - 1966 (Reel 63, Box-folder 50: 7)
  - 1967 (Reel 64, Box-folder 50: 8)
  - 1968 (Reel 64, Box-folder 50: 9)
  - 1969 (Reel 64, Box-folder 50: 10)
  - 1970 (Reel 64, Box-folder 50: 11)
  - 1970 (Reel 64, Box-folder 51: 1)
  - 1971 (Reel 64, Box-folder 51: 2)
  - 1972 (Reel 64, Box-folder 51: 3)
  - 1973-1976 (Reel 64, Box-folder 51: 4)
- Writings by Others,., 1929-1966 (Reel 65, Box 52)
  Articles, papers, reports, speeches and writings, arranged alphabetically by name of author
  - Aleksić, Bogosav (Reel 65, Box-folder 52: 1)
  - Bićanić, Rudolf (Reel 65, Box-folder 52: 2)
  - Clement, Mark (Reel 65, Box-folder 52: 3)
  - Čubrilović, Branko (Reel 65, Box-folder 52: 4)
  - Digby, M. (Reel 65, Box-folder 52: 5)
  - Djordjević, V. (Reel 65, Box-folder 52: 6)
  - Fotić, Konstantin (Reel 65, Box-folder 52: 7)
  - Gladstone, William Ewart (Reel 65, Box-folder 52: 8)
  - Hill, Elizabeth (Reel 65, Box-folder 52: 9)
  - Jefremović, B. (Reel 65, Box-folder 52: 10)
  - Kijaković, Jozo (Reel 65, Box-folder 52: 11)
  - Kostić, Boško N. (Reel 65, Box-folder 52: 12)
  - Lotin, Dimitrije (Reel 65, Box-folder 52: 13)
  - Maček, Vladko (Reel 65, Box-folder 52: 14)
  - Marković, Milorad (Reel 65, Box-folder 52: 15)
  - Mihajlov, Mihajlo (Reel 65, Box-folder 52: 16)
  - Mihajlović, General (Reel 65, Box-folder 52: 17)
  - Minih, Mihailo (Reel 65, Box-folder 52: 18)
  - Mitrović, Živan (Reel 65, Box-folder 52: 19)
  - Pantelić, Vojislav D. (Reel 65, Box-folder 52: 20)
  - Pavlović, Ilija M. (Reel 65, Box-folder 52: 21)
  - Pavlović, Jovan (Reel 65, Box-folder 52: 22)
  - Ristić, Borisav (Reel 65, Box-folder 52: 23)
  - Roberts, Walter (Reel 65, Box-folder 52: 24)
  - Šajković, Ivan (Reel 65, Box-folder 52: 25)
  - Simović, Dusan (Reel 65, Box-folder 52: 26)
  - Stanišić, M. M. (Reel 65, Box-folder 52: 27)
  - Topalović, Živko (Reel 65, Box-folder 52: 28)
  - Trivunac, Stevan (Reel 65, Box-folder 52: 29)
  - Vurdelja, Dragoljub G. (Reel 65, Box-folder 52: 30)
  - Živadinović, Stevan (Reel 65, Box-folder 52: 31)
  - Miscellaneous (Reel 65, Box-folder 52: 32)
- Incremental Materials of 1994., 1940-1942, undated. (Reel 66, Box 53-54)
  Financial records, memoranda, and correspondence relating to the Yugoslav Legation in Moscow and an untitled manuscript. Arranged chronologically
  - Yugoslav Legation in Moscow, 1940-1942 (Reel 66, Folder 53-54)
    - Inventory book of regulations and books received, 1940 (Reel 66, Box-folder 53: 1)